good evening ladies and gentlemen a very
warm welcome to ICI Lombard General
Insurance company limiteds Q2 and H1 fy4
earnings conference call from the Senior
Management we have with us today Mr
barav Das Gupta MD and CEO of the
company Mr gopal balachandran CFO and
cro Mr sanjie mantri executive director
and Mr alok aaral executive
director please note that any statements
comments are made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involves risk and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the cut being
expressed as a reminder all participant
lines will be in the listen only mode
and there will be an opportunity for you
to ask questions after the presentation
concludes should you need assistance
during the conference call please signal
an operator by pressing star 10 on the
Touchstone
phone I now hand the conference over to
Mr bav Das Gupta MD and CEO ICICI lombar
General Insurance Limited thank you and
all sir thank you ziko and good evening
to each one of you thank you for joining
the earnings conference call of I lumbar
General Insurance Limited company for Q2
and H1
f24 let me give you a brief overview of
the industry Trends and developments
that we have witnessed in the past few
months post this our CFO Mr gopal
balachandran will share the financial
performance of the company for the
quarter and the half year ended
September 30
2023 the global economy is experiencing
experiencing a loss of momentum however
the Indian economy is gaining strength
led by domestic drivers such as private
consumption and fixed asset Investments
by public sector
CeX the Southwest Monsoon rainfall
recovered during September however it
ended below the long period average the
manufacturing and services pmis and
other high frequency indicators ex
exhibited a robust expansion during this
quarter on the demand front Urban
consumption is buyant while rural demand
is showing some signs of Revival however
the current geopolitical conditions and
high interest rates in the advanced
economies can impact Global and domestic
economic growth negatively and we have
to Be watchful of the same for the
quarter as per data published by CM the
new Private Car Sales continue to
deliver robust growth year on year the
two wheer sales registered moderate
growth for the quarter and in terms of
volume Still Remains below the pre-
pandemic levels the commercial vehicle
growth was driven by growth in infra and
other core sectors health insurance
continue to deliver Rober growth growth
remaining the largest contributed to
overall growth the commercial segment
witness growth in line with the current
market environment we remain optimistic
that the industry will continue to grow
given the favorable macros regulatory
changes low penetration and relatively
positive consumer
sentiment speaking of the performance
The General insurance industry delivered
a gdpi growth of 14.9% for the first
half of this year over the first half of
last year excluding the crop insurance
growth is at 18% for the same period
overall the underwriting performance
worsen with a combined ratio of the
industry at 113.0 for q1 fi4 as against
11.4 for q1
fi23 for motor business while the combin
ratio continues to remain elevated the
combin ratio for the industry improved
to
12.1% from q1 2024 as against 124.5 for
q1
2023 moving to the business numbers for
us in Q2 fi 2024 the company grew at
17.4% as compared to the industry growth
of 12
12.5% in terms of growth for key
segments during the quarter Property and
Casualty line of business grew at 17.2%
which was higher than the industry
growth of
8.6% further during the quarter we acced
market share across all segments such as
fire Marine engineering and
liability in motor our growth for the
quarter was 10.9% as against the
industry growth of 13.9%
the growth in motor segment was aided by
robust growth of 37.6% in the new
Private Car segment the private car mix
stands at 51.8% for the for this quarter
while the competitive intensity the
motor segment remained elevated we
continue our focus of developing a
quality portfolio based on granular data
we continue to rebalance our portfolio
resulting in commercial vehicle mix at
22.1% and two wheer mix at 26.1% for
Quarter Two of this
year we also Contin to hardness our
digital capabilities in building claims
efficiency in motor in Q2 fi4 through
our preferred partner Network PPN
Network we were able to service 63% of
our non OEM claims up from 44% in Q2 of
2023 the health segment continues to be
the fastest growing segment for the
industry during this quarter we grew at
20.3% as a result of our continued
investment in retail Health distribution
we have grown in line with the industry
at
18.7% this was driven by growth in
business s to the retail health agency
vertical of
21.7% I would also like to share that
our onstop solution for all insurance
and wellness needs I take care app has
surp surpassed 6.9 million uh user
download till date the incremental
download for the quarter was 1.3 million
for Q2 of fi 24 the premium Source
through I take care app contributed to
88457 million to the overall gdpa
reflecting a 3. five times increase year
on
year we have been updating you about our
digital business initiatives like
digital wand and I take care which we've
been driving in an agile manner we are
now scaling these agile models to
business lines across the company
completely re redefining the ways of
working and the business processes
coupled with the transformation of the
core system we expect this to be a key
driver for our future growth as a
digitally impart insurance
company As You Are all uh you may be
aware I have decided to pursue an
overseas opportunity after spending over
14.5 years with ICA Lombard it has been
a wonderful Journey for me and I'm
grateful for the collective support of
all our stakeholders our employees
customers Channel Partners analysts and
shareholders we have made large strides
in the industry and made I a much loved
brand brand as India's largest private
sector GI player I take this opportunity
to thank all of you for your support and
hope you will extend the same support as
I pass on the beton to my dear colleague
sanjie
Mani sanjie has been with the i group
for over 20 years sanjiv has played a St
Stellar role in terms of his achievement
within the company he spearheaded the
retail division as an executive director
where he was leading distribution of
products across agency Bank Insurance
direct and Alternate channels he was
also in charge of the strategy products
pricing marketing and corporate
communication vertical at IC Lombard I'm
convinced that IC Lombard will continue
to be a strong force of positive change
in the industry under his leadership
over to you s thank you bar your lead
ship is an inspiration for all of us and
the St record over the last 15 years has
left an indelible impact on the
organization and the industry at large
we are excited for you and the
opportunities that lie ahead and wish
you the very best I'm keenly looking
forward to taking the journey ahead and
we rely heavily on the support of all
our stakeholders these are interesting
times for the G industry and we're very
well positioned to capitalize on this I
look forward to meeting and interacting
with each one of you personally we will
continue to remain focused on our
overall philosophy of balancing growth
and
profitability I will now request gopal
to take you through the financial
numbers for the Recently concluded
quarter and half year
thanks to each one of you I now give you
a brief overview of the financial
performance of the recently concluded
quarter and half year we have uploaded
the results presentation on our website
you can access it as we walk you through
the performance numbers the gr direct
premium income of theany was at R 24.72
billion in H1 f524 as against R 10 15.55
billion in H1 fi23 a growth of 18.2% as
against industry growth of
14.9% excluding crop GDP of the company
was at
17.6% which was in line with industry
growth of 18% in quarter to
f524 gdpi was at 6.86 billion in Q2 as
against 51.85 billion rupees in Q2 fi23
a growth of 17. 4% this growth was
higher than the industry growth of
12.5% our gdpi growth during the quarter
was primarily driven by growth in the
preferred segments the overall gdpi of
our Property and Casualty segment grew
by 17.2% at 14.76 billion rupees in
quarter to fi 24 as against R 12.59
billion in quarter to
fi23 on the retail side of the business
GDP of the motor segment was at R 2.38
billion in quarter 2 fi 24 as against r
19.28% fi23 registering a growth of
10.9% the advanced premium numbers was
at rupes
32.892880
billion in Q2 fi23 registering a growth
of
20.3% our agents which included the
point of sale distribution count was at
461 as on September 30 2023 up from
around
17,49 as on June 30 2023 GDP of the
retail Health segment grew by
19% Group Health segment that's the
corporate employer employee segment grew
by 20.6% during the quarter the bank
assurance and kg group grew at 24.3%
this quarter during the quarter of
business source through our digital one
team grew by
26.7% overall our digital Focus has
enabled us to increase our digital
revenues which includes the IL take care
app Business to rupees 3.66 billion
which accounts for 6% of our overall
gdpi for the
quarter Rec resultantly the combined
ratio was 103.7 for H1 fi 24 as against
10 14.6% for H1
fi23 excluding the impact of cat losses
of r83 billion in H1 fi4 and r28 billion
in H1 fi23 the combined ratio was 10
12.7% and 10 14.2% respectively combined
ratio was 13.9% in quarter to fi 24 as
against 10 5.1% in quarter to fi23
excluding the impact of C leses of r48
billion in Q2 f524 and r28 billion in Q2
fi23 the combined ratio was 10 2.8% and
10 14.3% respectively our investment
assets Rose to rupes 4 23.12 billion as
at September 30 2023 up from rupes 44905
billion as at June 30 2023 our
investment leverage net of borrowings
was 4.07 times as at September 30 2023
as againsted 4.16 times as at June 30
2023 investment income was at rupes
17.59%
R 9.36 billion in Q2 fi 24 as against
rupes 7.39 billion in Q2
fi23 our capital gains net of
empowerment on investment assets stood
at rupes 2.87 billion in H1 fi 24 as
compared to rupes 1.43 billion in H1
fi23 capital gains net of impairment on
investment assets stood at rupes 1.65
billion in Q2 fi4 as compared to rupes
1.11 billion in Q2 fi23 our profit
before tax grew by 19.4% at R 12.84
billion in H1 fi 24 as against R 10.75
billion in H1 fi23 whereas PBT grew by
25.3% at 7.64 billion in Q2 f524 as
against rupes 6.10 billion in Q2 fi23
consequently profit after the tax grew
by 3% at R 9.68 billion in H1 fy4 as
against 9.40 billion in Hy H1 fi23 fact
degw by 2.2% Ates 5.77 billion in Q2 fi4
from rupes 5.91 billion in Q2
fi23 operator request has been initiated
if you'd like to cancel this request
please press zero again 2% in H1
f24
and 24.8% in Q2
f524 return on average it was 18% in
hman
f24
fi23 the RO for quarter 2 fi 24 was
21.1% as against 24.5% in quarter 2 fi23
soleny ratio was at 2.59 times as at
September 30th 2023 as against 2.53
times as at June 30 2023 continued to be
higher than the regulatory minimum
requirement of 1.5 times the board of
directors of the company has declared
inm dividend of rupes 5 per share for H1
fi2 24 as against rupes 4.5 per share
for H1
fi23 as I conclude I would like to
reiterate we continue to stay focused on
driving profitable growth sustainable
value creation and safeguarding the
interest of policy holders at all times
I would like to thank you all for
attending this earnings call and we will
now be happy to take any specific
questions that you have thank you thank
you very much we will now begin the
question and answer session and anyone
who wishes to ask a question may press
star and one on the Touchstone telephone
if you wish to withdraw yourself from
the question Q you may press star and
two participants are requested to use
hand while asking a question ladies and
gentlemen we will wait for a moment
while the question Q
assembles
our first question is from the line of
ainash Singh from MK Global please go
ahead yeah hi good evening uh thanks for
the opportunity uh uh best wishes to you
Vargo for your future endeavors and
congratulations to Sanju on his new role
uh uh good set of performance couple of
questions uh first one uh I mean on your
motor side of course you commented about
the competitive intensity uh but
whatever I see incrementally in your
quarter two overall motor profitability
seems to be quite good for you yet you
remain sort of very very guarded with
the motor I mean so why such I would say
the guarded approach even when
profitability seems to be suggesting
that okay uh things are better than what
they were a few quarters back so that is
on your entire strategy around motor
because even in motor CV you have
started to sort of a uh take a bit of
more business but again there you it
seems that okay you have sort of try to
slow down so on on overall motor I would
like to understand the philosophy and on
the same point now I guess if I
understand the regulation correctly now
even motor TP technically a commission
is sort of a possible because I mean the
business line wise commission caps are
gone so what is sort of a practices you
are witnessing in the market as far as
motor is concerned so that's on motor
and on health
uh I of course I see that okay uh the
results are coming from your focus on
agency and that sort of leading to sort
of a growth in retail yet if I see
because you are growing uh strongly in
the group both on the banker side as
well as the employer employee uh your
mix is Shifting again more towards uh
group I mean of course the Bankai is
largely retail I understand yet I'm
think that on your individual side uh I
mean is that growth still a bit you
calibrated
or why I mean uh because on the group
employers employe side if I understand
the price hike is now behind so it would
be largely kind of a volum l growth so
that growth is a strong B growth is
strong is I mean so on the pure pure
retail why sort of a bit of slow as for
your own experience so the two question
thank
you thanks and maybe sanj can answer the
question yeah sure so thanks aash
clearly from a motor perspective as you
rightly said uh there are enough and
more Tails available at the industry
level and we are well set to capitalize
uh in a way in your question itself I
see the answer that we are able to drive
it profitably because we have kept
ourselves calibrated and we've also
always maintained that we will move
where we see an opportunity in terms of
profit pool uh if you look at our own uh
configuration of motor portfolio overall
you will see that the CV portfolio has
marginally gone down in terms of a
contribution in hedge fund of 23.4 it
moved to 2 1.6 and we have grow on
private car and two wheer as a company
uh if you ask me in terms of the view
the way we expect ourselves we we would
continue to exert what is required uh
but if you see intensity which is uh in
our mind not working out overall we will
probably be attacked cous in terms of
driving it so overall our plan of uh
being a competitive and being in this
play because this is where a key
distribution is we will continue to
exert ourselves as a team uh on the
health part which you spoke about in
terms of growth coming Prim from Group
Health rather than retail uh if you see
our investment largely has been on the
retail side and there you'll see a Delta
over industry growth of 2% uh Group
Health we always maintained that we
going strategically if we see that we
are able to uh see some sanity in terms
of pricing we go deep that's what we do
in quarter one but in Quarter Two If you
see we have grown rather subdued Vis is
the market uh that plan per se for us as
a company uh will not change but our
trajectory on the retail side is far
more permanent and you will see is doing
much better there's a marginal
Improvement in market share but I would
not like to read too much into that
because over a period of time we would
do much better and we continue to stay
invested as far as health agency is
concerned yeah thank you and that
question regarding you know current
practices around Commissions in motor
because I mean technically now I mean
one can pay commissions on motor 33 as
well so what sort of a market I mean
post the sort of you know basically the
commission caps are going to cap what
kind of a market practices you are
seeing as far as the payouts are
concerned so Avinash clearly we spoke
about the industry level numbers on
motor and we see a marginal Improvement
in the overall combined ratio from 124
is moved to 120 uh Frankly Speaking
there is not too much you can read in
those numbers as far as this you know
this point of time on expense of
management while it do come in you see
almost 50% of the company being more
than the limit which is there which is
stated uh have we seen uh overall
rationality prevailing across uh Frankly
Speaking the industry itself is
adjusting adjusting to it at this point
of time and over the period of time I do
believe that you will see far more
rationalization than what's happened now
and we we do expect stability to come in
by quarter three or quarter four in
overall from overall
perspective okay thank you thank
you thank you our next question is from
the line of sha Shivani from clsa please
go
ahead yes uh thank you for the
opportunity and congratulation on a good
set of numbers uh so so on the coming
back on the motor book I wanted some
more understanding on uh the loss ratio
Improvement that has happened in 1 H
versus 1q uh I know you don't want us to
look us on look at loss ratios on
quarterly basis but if uh even even the
1 numbers look quite good so that would
be one question uh second is on the uh
monthly performance so uh while I
understand your monthly performances do
vary but if you can give us some color
in uh understanding what specifically
happened in probably August and
September because still July you guys
were had a very strong run rate of about
20% so uh any color now around what
happened and any growth Outlook that you
can give and so so one more question
third question probably you've launched
a new product with IC pro life the
health and protection product uh
management mentioned in the conference
call yesterday so if you can give us
some understanding of the economics of
such a product you know uh premiums uh
the way uh partnership with IC Pro works
out I'm assuming this will get sold on
the IC bag platform so some color on
that yeah so so sh I think on the first
one I think if you look at uh on the
loss ratios for motor um I think you're
right I think we keep saying that you
should never look at numbers uh over
quarters or even let's say even on a
financial year basis because some of
these lines will obviously kind of start
to exhibit U outcomes over a relatively
longer period of time particularly in
the context of motor third party uh
having said that I think when you look
at even for let's say the half year uh
on motor OD specifically in general what
we have talked about is the portfolio
loss ratio should kind of range between
this 5 to 70% kind of threshold on motor
own damage uh for the half year I think
that number is at let's say 65% or there
about but that's the range at which you
would possibly see depending on what
kind of a business mix that we write in
terms of whether we are able to
relatively pick pick up a higher
proportion of uh new or let's say
relatively what kind of proportion are
be able to write in the context of the
older portfolio so that's broadly the
range at which we will be able to
operate at within quarters obviously the
loss ratios will undergo a change but
that's the range that we are comfortable
with in so far as uh the own damage book
is concerned on third party again the
point is still the same I think while
for the quarter you would have again
seen the numbers slightly better or
let's say even on a half yearly basis uh
I think number stands at about 66% but
these are experiences that one should
logically again look at uh over
relatively longer periods uh and also to
the fact that depending on what kind of
a mix of business that we write in terms
of Private Car two-wheeler and CV and
that's something that we keep
calibrating from time to time
corresponding to which you could
possibly see a change in the loss ratio
uh experience uh but otherwise there's
nothing specific to call out in the
context of let's say uh the uh quarter
two numbers having said that I think
what we also keep doing is given the
fact that from a reserving perspective
generally we have tried to be prudent at
all points of time that philosophy still
continues to remain the same uh even as
we write whichever portfolio of the book
but over a period of time as you would
have seen some of our experiences have
actually started to turn out to be much
much positive and let's say what our
initial estimates have been so that will
obviously get calibrated from time to
time but otherwise in so far as over
portfolio is concerned it's purely a
function of what kind of mixes mix of
business that that we able to R just to
add to a point that goal made is that
the way we look at businesses on a
combined basis not just loss ratio and
overall you should study our numbers on
a combined perspective certain
businesses may have higher expenses uh
you know lower loss issue and byy versus
so as a as a team we look at overall
combin as a as a
object for for the combo product that
got Ved yes we really excited we have uh
taken the term and the CHR product of
our and given a combined offering to our
customers through our agency channel uh
if you look at it uh crew has a a very
decent agency practice and we have very
decent Bank practice and there was uh a
gap which needed to be filled we have
created this product line to you know
leverage on each other's distribution
and as for the regulat environment that
is there it's something which is a very
feasible option we have gone ahead and
done this uh partnership with them and
we expect this product to prob ramp up
in time to come uh to be very honest our
agents will require a bit of a training
and process will come with a lag over a
period of time but but that being said
we really excited with this partnership
that we have done with them to drive uh
the combo product in the market which in
many ways is first of its kind and last
questions sha on the monthly performance
numbers again I think that's purely a
function of uh what kind of businesses
do we write between periods uh as we had
explained even in the earlier call our
business do tend to have a bit of cality
across businesses
so for example in quarter one you will
obviously see a relatively higher
proportion of some of the commercial
lines being underwritten in Quarter Two
we do see businesses booked particularly
in the context of crop now that could
get booked in a in a particular month
and therefore to that extent you may
possibly see variations in growth
percentages uh when you look at it
relatively on a month- on- Monon basis
but here again as we keep saying I think
a better way to look at given the
cyclicality of the business that we get
get to see maybe for example quarter 3
you will see a lot more business largely
driven through let's say some of the
retail growth uh so again you may see
let's say month- on- Monon changes
between segments of businesses U but
however when you look at it on a full
year basis I think in line with what we
have spoken uh largely looking at
looking at the way how that how things
are positively shaping up for us uh we
should definitely look at ending the
year within that High Teens percentage
growth that we have talked about and uh
in general I mean depending on what sanj
also mentioned on the expense of
management side I think if things starts
to get uh improved much better from an
industry perspective then the relative
outperformance that we have talked about
of 10000 BSIS point over and above the
market growth rate that's something that
we still believe we will be able to
achieve got it sir thank you this
answers my question thank
you thank
you our next question is from the line
of nides from invest Tech please go
ahead uh thanks for the opportunity uh
uh what is the share of OEM and non OEM
business in the motor and how it has
been trending over last two to three
years overall if you see in our split in
terms of the M that they're speaking
about we will almost have 70% thereout
of a business coming from the OEM
business and the rest would be coming
through other channels which agency and
Bank
insurance so I think last year we
articulated Our intention to move
towards to increase share of non OEM uh
by focusing on high loss ratio low low
expense ratio uh business uh so how is
the progress on that has a share of non
OEM going up so uh overall if you see
again uh uh incrementally yes we intend
exercising ourselves more on the agency
side but uh the manner in which a motor
book has got created uh there's a fair
amount of contribution and if we see an
opportunity there it's not one for the
other will continue to invest
extensively on the agency business side
but that being said OEM where we have
been working for years in a build of
franchise we will continue to drive that
uh so we need to look at both of both of
these in a in a standalone there there
are times when o contribution can go
really up I mean I mean there's a season
coming in quarter 3 obviously you'll
find again OEM you know uh probably
showing a larger percentage but that
being said agency business should
continue to do well but relatively to
put percentage pool would be a very
difficult option it's not one for the
other so NES just to add to sub what
sanj said I think strategically and
philosophically while we are investing
there will be times when OEM will again
come back up right so if new vehicle
sales increase as has happened as we
said in the opening remarks uh I think
the share of new vehicle sales has been
very positive for us and those are
profitable pools so when we see those
opportunities we want to guard
it sure understood understood secondly I
noticed that there is some change in the
Senior Management Personnel uh structure
uh so uh if you can explain what is
rational for that and what is this
Emerging Market group uh if you can
share some details on that Emerging
Market group so effectively it's a very
minor change not a significant change
but we have an experienced resource
which has joined in and he's an expert
in terms of driving the emerging market
so we have pulled him in to report into
to Alo which otherwise had a multiple
reporting so we want to use the benefit
of his presence in the
system and Emerging Market group is a is
a commercial lines or Emerging
Market operates across channels and
business lines basically this is the you
know bat rather than the top cities
right so this is where if you remember
last year we had done a little bit of
you know structuring change where Al
agal who was Ed looking after after
wholesale business was given specific
Focus given charge of that that market
with specific focus and we are investing
and we are growing that business uh so
typically let's say the top 40 cities
would be not there but thereafter it
would be considered to
be sure thank you that's it from my side
thank you
thank ladies and gentlemen in order to
ensure that the management is able to
address questions from all participants
in the conference please limit your
questions to one or two per participant
should you have a follow-up question we
would request you to rejoin the queue
thank you our next question is from the
line of sanet G from Evis spark please
go ahead yeah uh thank you thank you for
the
opportunity my first question is that
whether whether you want to preone your
guidance of
102.5 to be achieved because because ex
of C cat if I see
you are almost there uh uh what what we
have thought we will achieve it by exit
of fi25 so so just wanted to understand
uh whether whether uh given given the
underwriting environment you believe
that could happen little quicker than
expected that's Point number one and and
second within within the uh this 102.5
or combined ratio Improvement uh means
the some some vage was expected to come
from the Opex part but despite U um our
Opex compared to last year still still
has has been higher or or in one also
it's higher so just wanted to understand
that eom is overall dragging the opics
low higher or increasing the Opex on the
higher side or or you believe sanity
will come and um will expense ratios
will improve for the sector
as sanit cut a bit of slack to the team
right I you know you just you delivering
better than expected numbers and that's
what we want to continue to do uh no
change in guidance as you know the
market is still very competitive we'
talked about the combined ISO for the
industry is in terms of motor share
motor segment uh but clearly I think
over the last one year the team has done
a brilliant job in terms of uh uh you
know significantly calibrating uh the
business as also building a lot of
capability on the cost side both on the
claims and and expense side uh so I
think you know we the team is doing
really well but there's no need to
change guidance as we see it at this
point in time on the cost side I'll ask
gopal to answer yeah so I think sanket
we will we will still continue to
maintain what we have been kind of
talking about which is uh I think the
businesses has always have to be looked
at as what Baro also just mentioned in
response to the earlier one which is we
always look at the businesses from an
overall combined perspective uh because
different businesses would obviously
have a mix of let's say loss experience
and let's say the expense ratios as well
uh just to kind of uh look at the
overall expense of management
specifically to answer your point uh
first half of last year our expense of
management was at
27.3 relative to that if you look at our
first half of this year we are at about
26.9 so hence to that extent even from
an eom perspective we have actually seen
a marginal Improvement in line with what
we definitely wanted to kind of drive it
towards and this is despite the fact
that we continue to make our investments
in those areas of building Distribution
on health agency technology some of the
core transformation project that we
talked about I think clearly we would
want to continue to make those
Investments and hence to that extent you
may not suddenly see a big shift
happening in so far as specifically in
the context of the expense ratio numbers
are concerned we will obviously Drive uh
a a positive change but having said that
I think we will directionally be more
Guided by the other objective that we
have specifically spelled out which got
rated as we speak which is the combined
ratio objective of 102% is something
that we want to achieve by the end of
next year so that's something that we
want to clearly Drive and as I said
purely uh the breakdown of expense is
function of loss and expenses got it got
it just last two questions one question
which is one data keeping typical loss
ratio of retail health and Group Health
uh that that if you can share and second
just just wanted to understand this IL
take care app 6% of gwp is is a big big
achievement so so um how do you see this
to be contributing and and and if you
can give a color how much is mix driven
by motor and helping in I te
care so so the number of 6% is the
digital contribution uh s the second
Point second part of your question uh so
therefore to that extent that also
includes let's say the business that we
Source through I take care app and as we
have been talking about I think
consistently whether you look at it on a
year- on-ear basis obviously there is a
multiplier increase in so far as the
premium that you are souring through I
take care is concerned roughly about 3.7
times increase that we have seen uh but
even when you look at it on a sequential
basis I think we have been able to kind
of grow the contributions coming in
through that particular uh particular
app so we are very very excited with the
way how things are getting played out
and um equally we are getting to see a
lot more uh product per customer in so
far as the use of the app is concerned
and that will continue to drive both
volumes as well as let's say value of
premium in so far as the digital
contribution is concerned uh to your
first point in so far as the breakdown
of the loss ratios are concerned I think
for water two uh the breakdown of the
overall health loss ratios into
corporate health and Retail Indemnity
corporate Health loss ratios are at
about 102% and the retail Health
Indemnity loss ratios are
66.6% now this number I think when when
the numbers that we gave out for quarter
one last year corporate Health was about
92.6 and the retail Health inity numbers
for 64.2 now obviously these numbers
have to be looked at in the context of
how do we see some of the loss
insurances play out and particularly in
quarter 2 we do get to see a slight
increase in loss Insurance because
typically it's a monsoon season and we
get to see a lot more increase in uh
health related ailments that we get to
see and this is not specifically only
for this particular quarter too even
otherwise when you look at it even for
the last year for example clearly we had
seen an increase in the loss ratios
laying out between let's say a quarter
two versus a quarter one so hence in
that sense I think we are pretty much
okay with the way how the loss
experiences is playing out and as we had
indicated in so far as the portfolio
growth is concerned I think it is coming
at a price at which we are comfortable
with and uh in the subsequent quarters
we should start seeing some of these
loss ratios getting normalized
particularly in the context of lowering
down of loss insurances that we see in
Q3 and Q4 just to supplement what gopal
said you know and we've talked about
this in the past the entire thought
process uh and the and the approach
behind take care was uh consumer
engagement right engaging with our
customers be it you know uh the employer
employee segment where the individual is
a potential retail customer or a retail
customer b2c customer who comes on board
and uh and the approach that we are
taking is that as we have more engaged
customers they will renew better we will
have cross sale opportunities and
hopefully the relationship will be more
sticky so principally for us whatever
business we get as long as it's VI we
are not driving motor numbers or health
numbers there it's a customer engagement
app and uh and and as an organization we
don't want to split that number at this
point in time to say okay this is my
motor number this is my health number
because it might drive us in a manner
which is not customer centc uh so uh so
as an organization we've been giving the
numbers in terms of number of app
downloads the total volume of crale and
and upsale business that we're doing
which is something that we continue
to thank you sorry to Mr sanit G may we
request that you return to the question
Q for followup questions as there are
several participants waiting for their
turn thank you
sir our next question is from the line
of swab mukarji from bnk Securities
please go
ahead hi sir thank you for the
opportunity and congrats on a good set
of numbers so I again come back to you
know the motor loss ratios so uh I
understand that what you have
articulated in terms of uh your
experience uh and maybe some relases
that are coming uh but just you know for
a view of how the loss ratios are going
to pan out I mean say for in mot t uh
your loss ratios have been little bit
fluctuating over quarters uh right now
that there has been a bit of a
Improvement going ahead if you can get
some color for the fer how we should
think about this number where it can
sustain same for OD given that you you
are piing up on growth on the OD
business and particularly private
vehicle in the mix how confident would
you be in kind of maintaining this typ
of loss Rao so that is the first one and
uh secondly uh in terms of the
investment income I just wanted to
understand the yield that you have shown
uh realized return
is fairly strong I think slightly higher
than what we have done in the past so is
there certain uh you know Tactical bets
that have you know that have worked out
which might not play out in the coming
quarters so and what kind of e we can
think about of the you know going ahead
on a normalized basis yeah that's so up
on the first one I think which is what I
kind of responded uh to the earlier one
uh and one had kind of talked about the
range at which we would be comfortable
so one I think when we look at motor as
a line of business we obviously look at
it again more from a combined
perspective which will be a combination
of both the loss experience and let's
say the expense ratios and as what we
just discussed again it will depend on
what proportion of new business that we
write because new typically comes with a
relatively better loss experience and
correspondingly let's say the expense
ratios could slightly stay elevated and
correspondingly let's say the older
portfolios as we just discussed
typically comes with a slightly high LR
and let's say a relatively lower cost of
distribution so honestly that will be a
interplay that one one would get to see
in so far as writing this book is
concerned but having said that I think
the range at which one would be
comfortable to operate in the context of
motor own damage is what I had kind of
responded earlier which is in the range
of between 65 to 70% depending on what
kind of a business mix that we write in
the in in respect of proportion of uh
new or let's say the relatively older
portfolio on third party again pretty
much we have kind of talked about as
what I responded obviously we should
again not look at this numbers uh
particularly for quarters or let's say
even on a halfly basis you have to look
at the numbers over relatively longer
period uh so there again it will be a
function of what uh kind of loss
experiences that one sees but broadly I
would say that one could see the third
party loss ratios again kind of Hing
around what you see on a f year basis
that would be largely representative of
the range range at which we would get to
see the loss ratio play out so that's
the response uh your first one uh to
your second one on the overall uh
investment book uh I think uh in fact in
the past quarters people have been
asking us why have we not seen let's say
so much of an increase in the overall uh
interest income of the portfolio uh now
if you recollect I think what we
generally do is uh depending on the
market opportunity that one sees is how
we place our overall portfolio act and
for example we tend to kind of in this
High interest rate environment we
obviously want to capitalize the
opportunity that one sees and so far as
uh approval to the book is concerned and
which is why our overall uh duration of
the book u in fact stands at about 5.23
years this number if I remember it
correctly uh at the end of the at the
beginning of the year uh was at about
4.99 years so obviously we have gone a
bit long and we have kind of rightly
positioned the portfolio in order to
capitalize as I said the increased uh
interest rat that one sees in the market
so hence to that extent we will
obviously get to see this kind of play
out even as we kind of head into the
subsequent quarters what is it that you
will not necessarily see playing out
over the subsequent period is purely a
function of the extent of capital gains
that one sees in the market that's
purely driven by let's say the market
opportunity that one sees and even in
the past we have talked about it uh
between quarters you can always see
fluctuations in the breakup of the
overall investment income uh depending
on how Market plays out is what you will
be able to see some kind of gam playing
out so so hence to answer your point I I
think uh the way we are positioned the
portfolio is what is helping us in terms
of capitalizing the uh increased uh uh
interest uh
income and just to just to supplement
the point that gopal made uh this we've
been talking about this that our carried
yield will increase and Go's given this
number if you also look at the split of
the unrealized gains the unrealized gain
in the equity book has increased uh at
the end of this quarter uh obviously on
the debt side on the bond side it's come
down because interest rates have gone
gone up but that is not something that
we worried about because these are all
uh calls that we've taken to stay long
in uh in the Deb Market that's how our
yield has
increased understood sir yeah but thank
you so much and all the best thanks
thanks
much thank you our next question is from
the line of Rishi junjun Wala from iifl
institutional equities please go ahead
yeah thanks for the opportunity just a
couple of questions uh uh firstly you
know this September month would have
seen the first 5-year anniversary of the
two-wheeler long-term TP um so how has
the experience been in terms of renewal
it is you know given that 5 years of TP
means that the renewals have pretty much
down to zero and and as a result uh you
know if you can give some color in terms
of what would you know that amount of
premium for September month be as
proportion of overall motor
TP so uh thanks uh clearly yes this was
the first month uh overarchingly if you
ask me over the industry level there's a
good reason why I think Supreme Court
get the verdict in terms of having
long-term this uh the retention rates uh
continue to be relatively on the lower
side I would not split enough of the
amount but retention level that we are
seeing as a team right now is around 15
to 20% uh development of this uh will
happen over you know sumission of
probably a quarter in terms of what are
the two numbers because we'll have to
pursue this uh uh with our own customers
and see where we end up losing it uh but
it's but it's something as a pool that
we very ke so we're using all possible
analytics to see if we can further
sharpen our X and see that uh we can
drive these numbers uh even if it's only
TP we'll be more than happy to ride this
pool understood and the second is uh
just on the total payouts to the
distribution uh channels um you know
some of our uh life insurance peers have
talked about U you know industrywide
increase in payouts uh to the
distribution channels um how has it
behaved uh for us uh in the the Key Bank
partner Channel as well as outside of
that uh in terms of the total payout I
understand there was you know uh you
know categorization or reclassification
but just in in terms of payout has there
been uh demand for increase in payouts
for us and uh have you seen any kind of
anomalies in the industry otherwise so
uh overall if you see for us as a
company expense of management has stayed
within the range uh and in fact it's
come down uh from a 27.3 to 26.9 uh so
Frankly Speaking uh there is no
accelerated increase but in certain
Pockets there's we have seen a bit of an
acceleration you will see that
dynamically we will go again to what our
basic thesis has been we will change
where we can get uh viable business uh
in terms of acquiring it uh in a way to
some extent you can see our motor market
share also is reflecting that we had a
calibrated growth uh to prob maintain
profitability over just market share
growth so you can read in terms of
what's Happening overarchingly uh but
overall will seem to be in control
uh at this point of
time okay thank you so much yeah than
thanks thank you our next question is
from the line of PES Jen from Mo lawal
please go
ahead Mr PR Jen your line has been
unmuted you can
go hi congratulations on great set of
members uh firstly uh you know I just
missed the agency count number can you
just repeat
that it's about 1 lak 122,000 which
includes the agency that includes the
point of sale distribution as well so
this was it is 1 lak 122,000 this number
at the end of uh uh earlier period was
about
13,000 okay okay and just on the prev
question sorry to interrupt J may we
request you to use your answer please as
your audio is Sir thank you is this
better hello hello your voice is
slightly more feeble uh PR we can't hear
you
clearly s I'll come back in the KE sorry
thank you
sir our next question is from the line
of mukar L from noama wealth management
please go
ahead I uh good evening and
congratulations on a good set of numbers
couple of questions uh one we seeing a
good increase in the crop business uh
that you're doing this year what is the
philosophy uh behind that uh I remember
in the past you wanted to avoid that
business and uh I I also know that you
got this business again from bti uh so
is that only those States or are you
also growing some of the other
states uh so that's that's one second uh
again I'm just going back to the
guidance of H % given that your
performance is quite strong and you know
in first half itself you are at
102.7 so uh are you being a little bit
too
conservative over
here um and finally um you know most of
the industry is uh ahead sorry is not
meeting the uh eom uh Norms right now um
you know so what regulatory action can
we expect and and what would you say uh
by when uh will the regulator start
looking at this and implementing
this guys let me answer it in the same
sequence one on crop there is no change
in philosophy as gopal had explained
that I think sanj explained that there
are certain month where you book a
premium it just shows up in that quarter
uh in aggregate share of crop business
which we have guided the market was to
be would be around 5% of total business
uh for the annual business not on a
quartly basis and I think we'll stay at
at that kind of range we are not
significantly growing our crop book uh
in spite of the fact that we believe
some players in the market are trying to
do that because of the advantage that
they get on E but philosophically we
don't believe that's the right strategy
right approach so we are not doing that
uh uh there was some amount of booking
in the K season because most of the
business for us is in the kar Market K
period so it's it's a bit higher in this
quarter that's about all secondly most
of the propop that we got is in the 1810
model uh so it's a reasonably well-
contained uh business and our experience
in the last couple of years has been
very reasonably positive on the approach
that we
had in terms of your question on uh uh
combin
coming to question on combin to add you
know whether we are being conserv your
call you you take your own views about
whether we being combined conservative I
think as I said the guidance should
remain the same if you can outperform
all of you should be happy uh third in
terms of the regulatory action uh look
it's not for us to talk about what the
regulator will do uh but uh at least we
uh hope and we think that this time the
regulator is very serious about this
uh at the same time this is not about a
quarterly number that they're monitoring
they will monit they're given a leway
for a company on an annual basis and my
my my sense is that the end of the year
they look at who is improved and who's
not improved and who's gone beyond
30% uh so I think it would be wise for
most companies which are running at high
than that number I think it would be
wise for them to bring it under control
but as I said it's not for us to talk
about what the regulator will do that's
a question that uh in a sense your time
will give us the answer and you'll see
what the regulator does thanks just a
follow up on this sir are we seeing a
heightened comparative intensity in the
group health segment also uh to sort of
meet the E Norms I think go answered
that and you know in the first quarter
we saw the market on gral to be better
and we had a much higher share uh this
quarter we've seen some amount of uh
aggression and in fact we've seen some
otherwise sensible companies by very
large chunky groupal businesses our
senses is probably to manage the extense
of management but at the end of the day
business is not just about expensive
management business is about combined
right so you to do it in a manner which
is sensible so uh We'll Be watchful uh
and we'll see what what happens but
overall at this point in time we are
quite comfortable with the group Heth
business that we
writing got it uh thank you and all the
best thank you and next question is from
the line of nishin Chaat from kotak
institutional equities please go ahead
uh thanks for taking my question uh just
a small one uh you when I look at the
monthly uh you know monthly figures for
motor TP business I was just curious
that uh you know did you do any
transaction in the last month uh you
know just say something that you had
done probably in the Feb or March month
last year no n they have not done any
transaction perfect thanks that answers
my question thank
you thank
you our next question is from the line
of supratim data from Ambit Capital
please go
ahead thanks for the opportunity uh just
wanted to understand a few things so one
the 0.48 billion of you know ncat losses
which lines of business are those
attributed
to it's been largely so this quarter uh
has been largely let's say relatively
retail uh so we have had a higher
proportion of losses coming in from the
motor line of business but equally we
have also had some amount of claims
coming in on the property side unlike
water one where relatively the uh losses
of roughly about 35 crores which was the
cat losses in q1 that was largely
property heavy as compared to
Motors got and uh within so if I adjust
for that ncat losses then in the motor
OD line then that would result in the
loss ratio being lower than 60% is that
a correct assumption and then my
followup question to that is you know
how sustainable is this loss ratio going
forward uh so uh so I kind of already
responded to that but just to kind of
rate rate uh again we will keep saying
this and you will get to hear us from
time and again you should never look at
quarterly numbers uh and largely it is
better to kind of look at numbers more
on yearly just to kind of rate rate on
motor own damage I think the loss ratio
depending on the kind of mix of business
that we write in motor we are
comfortable at a loss ratio range
between 65 to 70% uh that's the range
depending on what what kind of mix of
business we write and on TP again it's
better to kind of look at more annual
numbers uh which is largely reflective
of the loss ratio range that one would
be comfortable writing so hence to that
extent whether you adjust it for the
quarter to losses from cat in the loss
ratios but if you do that on a simple
basis then obviously yes the loss ratio
will definitely look better than what
the reported numbers are but having said
that I think the range at which we are
comfortable at is between 65 to uh 70%
and what equally we need to remember is
that whatever be the amount of losses I
think we do have uh appropriate
reinsurance support such that uh if
there's a very large uh Cat event having
an impact on the net that gets
appropriately protected through
necessary reinsurance
management got it and just one last
question so on the fire side there has
been a Slowdown in the second quarter so
just wanted to understand how much of
this is due to the IID burn rates being
removed uh versus you know overall
competition or you know you wanting to
not write some kind of business so just
wanted to so on that the experience as
what we discussed at the in the in the
first quarter is the sale which is that
roughly about 5 6% reduction from the
earlier rat which is uh better than what
we had actually we had anticipated at
the beginning of the year we have to see
if this holds in terms of fire there are
you know maybe one or two large policies
that have got moved from period to per
you know you know and there some uh you
know policies have earlier booked in
this period which may have got moved
somewhere else you should look at the
numbers with a longer period rather than
just a quarter the only thing just to
add to that I think having said that I
think if you look at across segments on
the commercial lines I think we still
continue to outperform the market I
think we continue to accreate market
share uh in s line of business or
whether you take any of the other
commercial lines we continue to outgrow
the
market it uh thank you that's very
helpful thank you ladies and gentlemen
due to time constraint that was the last
question of our question and answer
session I would now like to hand the
conference over to Mr bav Das Gupta for
closing
comment uh thank you thank you everyone
uh I think all of you have been great
support to uh to the company and me
personally and I really want to take
this opportunity to thank all of you for
being a great analyst and and investors
in our company uh as I said earlier I'm
hoping that you'll continue to engage
with us as you have in the past and
sanjie wants to have the last
word no I think absolute pleasure and uh
really Keen to interact with each one of
you personally as in when uh uh your
schedule permits uh nothing much to add
but absolutely in agreement with love
that uh we've had you know great inputs
and discussions with all of you and that
continues thank you so much and let's
meet up soon thank
you thank you thank you on behalf of ICI
Lombard General Insurance Company
Limited that concludes this conference
thank you for joining us and you may now
disconnect your lines